Guide to the Alva I. Cox Jr. Papers
Yale University Divinity School Library
- Church-Related (General), Series I
  - About the Church
    - "Video One--Program #125"; This is a Presbyterian television magazine. This particular program includes stories about Equal Employment Opportunity, Inclusive Language Lectionary, Those Who Wait, and Resurrection Celebration. (VHS: 2 copies), March 1983 (Box 1, Box 41)
    - "Video One--Program #125" (U-matic tape) (Box 63)
  - Liturgy
    - "All the Words in Webster's Aren't Enough..."; Filmstrips about Advent, Christmas-Epiphany, Lent, and Easter, with LP to accompany (LP: 1; filmstrips: 8 volumes; 2 copies of vol. 1-4, 1 copy of vol. 5-8 (Box OV10)
    - "Archdiocese Chapel--Icons" (Beta Master), Jan. 4, 1994 (Box 1)
    - "Archdiocese Chapel--Icons" - "Dub Selects"; Raw footage excerpts from interviews about Icons, Tribute, and Unity Theme. (VHS) (Box 1)
    - "Lectionary Committee"; Translators discussing gender-inclusive language. (audio cassette), Feb. 12, 1982 (Box 116)
    - "NRSV: A Standard for Our Time";This film is about the New Revised Standard Version Bible (NRSV). Developments within the past 40 years, such as recent changes in the English language as well as discoveries such as the Dead Sea Scrolls, necessitated a new standard translation: the NRSV. Final version (VHS 2 copies, one VTC), 1992 December 11; 1 (Box 1, Item barcode 39002098994222)
    - "NRSV: A Standard for Our Time"; Raw footage used in the making of this film. (Beta: 5 volumes), Sep. 27, 1990 (Box 2)
    - "NRSV: A Standard for Our Time"; Raw footage used in the making of this film (VHS) (Box 2)
    - "O For a Thousand Tongues to Sing"; Hymns sung by a choir. (audio cassette) (Box 116)
    - "Religion in the U.S.S.R."; Raw footage/selects from a Russion Orthodox Mass (VHS: 2 volumes) (Box 125)
    - "World Day of Prayer"; A 1-minute spot for television about World Day of Prayer. (VHS) (Box 2)
  - Church Youth
    - "African Youth and Students: The Impact of Christian Witness"; A Christian youth conference in Africa. (Beta), No date; 1 (Box 3, Item barcode 39002098994230)
    - "African Youth and Students: The Impact of Christian Witness" (VHS) (Box 3)
    - "By Faith: Christian Students Among the Cloud of Witnesses"; This is a history of the Christian Student Movement, such as the YMCA and the YWCA. (U-matic Master), 1991; 1 (Box 70, Item barcode 39002098995971)
    - "By Faith: Christian Students Among the Cloud of Witnesses" (Beta and DVD) (Box 157)
    - "By Faith: Christian Students Among the Cloud of Witnesses" (VHS) (Box 29)
    - "By Faith 2" (D-2: 1 (Master), April 9, 1991 (Box 70)
    - "Karen Hartley"; Interview about youth ministry (audio cassette) (Box 116)
    - "David Lyons"; Interview about a student Missionary trip to Haiti. (audio cassette) (Box 116)
    - "Maury Bola Iga Open Forum"; Interview about the student movement reviving the church. (audio cassette) (Box 116)
    - Student Christian Conference "Celebrate!"; Raw footage from Student Christian Conference. (VHS: 23 volumes), Dec. 28, 1990 to Jan. 1, 1991 (Box 3–4, Box 142–146)
    - Student Christian Conference "Celebrate!"; Raw footage from Student Christian Conference (U-matic S: 40 volumes) (Box 84–87, Box 147–149)
    - "A Challenge to Our Generation"; This is raw footage of a speech by David Rowe at "Celebrate!" (U-matic) (Box 63)
    - "Celebrate" -Student Christian Conference; Louisville; Opening Session, 1990; 1 (Box 83, Item barcode 39002098996151)
    - "Celebrate" -Student Christian Conference; Louisville; Opening Session #2, 1990; 1 (Box 147, Item barcode 39002098996383)
    - "Celebrate" - Student Christian Conference; Louisville; Opening Session #4, 1990; 1 (Box 83, Item barcode 39002098996169)
    - "Celebrate" - Student Christian Conference; Louisville; Opening Session #5, 1990; 1 (Box 83, Item barcode 39002098996177)
    - ""Celebrate" - Student Christian Conference; Louisville; #10; Denominational Meeting; Anti-Racism workshop, Part 1, 1990; 1 (Box 83, Item barcode 39002098996185)
    - "Celebrate" - Student Christian Conference; Louisville; Anti-Racism workshop, Part 2, 1990; 1 (Box 83, Item barcode 39002098996193)
  - Church Conferences
    - "Oklahoma Conference"; Audio from a conference in Oklahoma. Many conditions (such as weather, economics, etc.) have created a farm crisis in Oklahoma and other states. This has created a ripe atmosphere for radical groups and radical thinking, such as the KKK and neo-Nazis. (audio cassettes: 4 volumes) (Box 114)
    - "Stewardship"; Raw footage from a conference focusing on how preaching makes a difference for stewardship. (some of these videos also are under the titles of "Fire and the Focus" and "Camera Master Reel"). (U-matic: 11 volumes), 1984 (Box 87–89)
  - The Church and Social Action
    - (Unlabeled black tape); A person speaks about evangelization, social action, liberation, and so forth in relation to Catholicism and South Americans (audio cassette) (Box 116)
    - "The Fighting Ministers"; This film is about ministers fighting on behalf of unemployed steelworkers. Often these ministers get into trouble with their own denominations because of their convictions and efforts. (VHS), No date; 1 (Box 4, Item barcode 39002098994248)
    - "Venture in Mission: The Episcopal Church, U.S.A." (VHS: 2 copies), No date; 2 (Box 143, Box 146, Item barcode 39002098996375)
      This film is about the Episcopal Church helping with a variety of societal issues, such as the Good Samaritan Center providing bi-lingual and bi-cultural education for preschoolers, the church helping push for low-income housing in predominantly African-American neighborhoods which have not been retaining their former populations, and providing a community and facilities for the elderly.
    - "Venture in Mission: The Episcopal Church, U.S.A." (16mm: 2 copies) (Box OV5)
    - Episcopal Audio Tapes; These interviews about the Episcopal Church most likely are material from the preliminary stages of making either "The Next Step" or "Venture in Mission." (audio cassette: 13 volumes) (Box 114)
    - "The Next Step"; This is an extension of the Venture in Mission program. The five basic functions of mission considered here are service, worship, evangelism, education, and pastoral care. Final Version (VHS: 2 copies), 1982; 2 (Box 143, Box 146, Item barcode 39002098996367)
    - "The Next Step";. Final Version (16mm) (Box OV16)
    - "The Next Step and Scenics"; slides from photographs taken in preparation of and for making the film. (box of slides) (Box OV9)
    - "Yes, A Difference: the Presiding Bishop's Fund for World Relief" (VHS: 2 copies), No date; 2 (Box 144, Item barcode 39002098996359, Box 146)
      This is a film about the worldwide involvements of the Presiding Bishop's Fund for World Relief, a fund which was founded in 1940 to help those fleeing from Nazi Germany.
    - "Yes, A Difference" ( 16mm) (Box OV15)
    - "Hope for New Life"; A film for the Presiding Bishop's Fund for World Relief. This fund helps bring refugees to the U.S. and the local churches help them integrate into the community while also providing opportunities for refugees to share their culture with the community. (VHS), No date; 1 (Box 4, Item barcode 39002098994255)
    - "Hope for New Life" (16 mm: 2 copies) (Box OV3)
    - "Refugee Tapes"; These tapes are about refugees coming to the U.S.A. (audio cassettes: 2 volumes) (Box 115)
    - N.F.N.; Raw footage from the Neighbor for Neighbor program. (VHS: 7 volumes), June 18-22, 1993 (Box 4–5)
    - Neighbor For Neighbor program #1, 1993; 1 (Box 5, Item barcode 39002098994263)
    - Neighbor For Neighbor program #2, 1993; 1 (Box 5, Item barcode 39002098994271)
    - Neighbor For Neighbor program #3, 1993; 1 (Box 5, Item barcode 39002098994289)
    - Neighbor For Neighbor program #4, 1993; 1 (Box 6, Item barcode 39002098994297)
    - Neighbor For Neighbor program #5, 1993; 1 (Box 6, Item barcode 39002098994305)
    - Neighbor For Neighbor program #8, 1993; 1 (Box 6, Item barcode 39002098994313)
    - Neighbor For Neighbor program #9, 1993; 1 (Box 6, Item barcode 39002098994321)
    - Neighbor For Neighbor program #10, 1993; 1 (Box 6, Item barcode 39002098994339)
    - Neighbor For Neighbor program #11, 1993; 1 (Box 7, Item barcode 39002098994347)
    - Neighbor For Neighbor program #12, 1993; 1 (Box 7, Item barcode 39002098994354)
    - Neighbor For Neighbor program #13, 1993; 1 (Box 7, Item barcode 39002098994362)
    - Neighbor For Neighbor program #14, 1993; 1 (Box 7, Item barcode 39002098994370)
    - "On the Other Side" (VHS) (Box 7)
      This film is about the USSR and the Church's struggle to survive and thrive in this Communistic country. Delegates were sent from the NCC to the USSR to address issues of religious freedom, human rights, etc.
    - "On the Other Side" (U-matic SP), No date; 1 (Box 64, Item barcode 39002098995880)
    - "On the Other Side" (VHS) (Box 7)
    - "Pilgrimage for Peace"; Special report on religious leaders making a "pilgrimage for peace" to the Middle East from the United States during the Gulf War. (VHS: Volume 1), 1991; 1 (Box 8, Item barcode 39002098994396)
    - "Pilgrimage for Peace"; Special report on religious leaders making a "pilgrimage for peace" to the Middle East from the United States during the Gulf War. (VHS: Volume 2), 1991; 1 (Box 8, Item barcode 39002098994404)
    - "Teaching Project Build" (VHS), No date; 1 (Box 7, Item barcode 39002098994388)
      This film is about Project Build, which prepares young men (primarily from the inner city) for entry into the building and construction trade apprenticeships. The program also helps older men to become journeymen.
    - "Teaching Project Build" (16 mm) (Box OV4)
    - "To Bring Good News" (VHS) (Box 8)
      This program is about the Church helping the hungry and homeless, helping with public policies for long-term solutions to these problems, chaplaincy for those suffering from AIDS, economic policies, etc.
    - "To Bring Good News" (U-matic), No date; 1 (Box 64, Item barcode 39002098995898)
    - "Welcoming the Children" (VHS and Beta), No date; 1 (Box 8, Item barcode 39002098994438)
      This is a program about child advocacy. It talks about the need to use church resources to help with the needs of children.
  - Ecumenical Dialogue/Conferences
    - "Ecumenical Development Initiative"; Raw footage from an ecumenical conference following the previous night's honorary dinner for Archbishop Iakovos. (VHS: 12 volumes; 3 copies), Feb. 1995 (Box 12–14, Box 152–153, Box 155–156)
    - "Ecumenical Development Initiative" (Beta: 24 volumes) (Box 9–12)
    - "Ecumenical Ensemble Music Cut"; Raw footage of a choir singing. (U-matic) (Box 64)
    - "Ecumenical Ensemble Music Cut" (Audio cassette) (Box 116)
    - "Jubilee Advent: A Report"; Ecumenical and Interfaith activities for the Jubilee in Washington, D.C. (VHS), Nov. 11, 1986 (Box 8)
    - "Jubilee Advent: A Report" Ecumenical and Interfaith activities for the Jubilee in Washington, D.C. (D-2), 1996; 1 (Box 65, Item barcode 39002098995906)
    - "Seeking the Common Good: A Challenge to Church and Synagogues" Final version (VHS), Sep. 29, 1993; 1 (Box 8, Item barcode 39002098994412)
      This film is about a conference of the National Council of Churches, U.S. Catholic Conference, and the Synagogue Council of America. It discusses social issues with which these groups have had a positive impact, and how they can work together in these areas.
    - "Seeking the Common Good: A Challenge to Church and Synagogues" Final versionn (D-2 Composite Digital; Master) (Box 89)
    - "Seeking the Common Good: A Challenge to Church and Synagogues" Resource Materials (Beta: 33 volumes), June 8-9, 1993 (Box 14–18)
    - "Seeking the Common Good: A Challenge to Church and Synagogues" Resource Materials (VHS: 11 volumes) (Box 19–20)
    - "Seeking the Common Good: A Challenge to Church and Synagogues" Resource Materials (VHS (VTC): 11 volumes) (Box 20–21)
    - "The Unity of the Church--Faith and Order and the Healing of Life" Final version (VHS -VTC), Oct. 12, 1995; 1 (Box 8, Item barcode 39002098994420)
      This film is about the Faith and Order program of ecumenism and features excerpts from the Faith and Order Symposium.
    - "The Unity of the Church--Faith and Order and the Healing of Life" Resource materials: "Hoyuge and Smith and Thangeraj"; (VHS) (Box 14)
    - "The Unity of the Church--Faith and Order and the Healing of Life" Resource materials: "Faith and Order--Selects"; (VHS) (Box 14)
  - Ecumenical Efforts in Society
    - "Advocates for Justice"; (VHS: 2 copies), Nov. 21, 1988 (Box 21–22)
      This is about an interfaith coalition of Protestants, Catholics, and Jews to affect economic policies. Its three areas of focus are: 1) Domestic human needs and economic policy, 2) Food and agricultural policy, 3) International development policy.
    - "Advocates for Justice" (U-matic: 2 copies; one a Master), 1988; 2 (Box 65, Item barcode 39002098995914)
    - "Innocent Until Proven Guilty: the Ecumenical Minority Bail Bond Fund"; This program provides money for minorities facing large amounts of bail. Final version (VHS: 2 copies; user guide: 2 copies), 1989 (Box 22)
    - "Innocent Until Proven Guilty: the Ecumenical Minority Bail Bond Fund" (U-matic), 1989; 1 (Box 67, Item barcode 39002098995930)
    - "Innocent Until Proven Guilty: the Ecumenical Minority Bail Bond Fund" Resource materials (VHS: 6 volumes) (Box 22–23)
    - "Innocent Until Proven Guilty: the Ecumenical Minority Bail Bond Fund" Resource materials (Beta: 4 volumes) (Box 23)
    - "Innocent Until Proven Guilty: the Ecumenical Minority Bail Bond Fund" Resource materials (U-matic S: 9 volumes) (Box 89–90)
    - "On Holy Ground--U.S. Russia Ecumenical Youth Work Camp" (VHS), No date; 1 (Box 23, Item barcode 39002098994446)
      This film is about young American Christian volunteers helping restore a 14th century Russian Orthodox monastery. This monastery, used as a prison and death camp for years by the KGB, had finally been returned to its rightful owners.
  - Missions
    - "Adventure in Mission" (Volunteers in Mission); (VHS), No date; 1 (Box 24, Item barcode 39002098994503)
    - "Missionaries: Ends of the Earth", 1991; 1 (Box 24, Item barcode 39002098994479)
      Part of a five video series of Christian-oriented documentaries about modern-day missionaries.
    - "Missionaries: Africa: The Fertile Ground", 1991; 1 (Box 24, Item barcode 39002098994453)
      Part of a five video series of documentaries on modern missionaries.
    - "Missionaries: Stony Ground", 1991; 1 (Box 24, Item barcode 39002098994495)
    - "Missionaries: Last Frontier", 1991; 1 (Box 24, Item barcode 39002098994461)
    - "Missionaries: Taking Sides", 1991; 1 (Box 24, Item barcode 39002098994487)
    - "SFS Mission is #7" (Filmstrips: 4 volumes; Guides: 2 volumes; LP) (Box OV9)
- National Council of the Churches of Christ in the U.S.A. (NCC), Series II
  - About NCC
    - "Arie Brower: Response/Acceptance Speech"; This is Arie Brouwer's acceptance speech for the presidency of the NCC. (VHS), Nov. 8, 1984 (Box 24)
    - "Arie Brower: Response/Acceptance Speech" (U-matic) (Box 81)
    - "Ed Espy / Arie Brower Memorial" (See entry under series heading "Individuals") (VHS) (Box 24)
    - "Concern, Confrontation, and Crisis (NCC At The Crossroads)" - Part 1 (VHS), No date; 1 (Box 25, Item barcode 39002098994511)
      A CBS News Program about a controversial NCC conference that includes groups asking to do away with the NCC and start anew.
    - "Concern, Confrontation, and Crisis (NCC at the Crossroads)" - Part 2, No date; 1 (Box 25, Item barcode 39002098994529)
    - "Confirming a Heritage: Embracing the Future" (VHS - VTC), Nov. 16, 1995; 1 (Box 25, Item barcode 39002098994537)
      This film is about the good accomplished by the NCC through various programs.
    - "Crossroads for Mission" Final version (VHS: 2 copies), Sep. 11, 1991; 2 (Box 25, Item barcode 39002098994545)
      This program is about the Interchurch Center at 475 Riverside Drive in New York City, NY.
    - "Crossroads for Mission" (D-2 Composite Digital) (Box 90)
    - "Crossroads for Mission" Resource Materials ( Beta: 5 volumes "ITC / TIC"), June 14, 1989 (Box 26)
    - "Waiting Upon the Lord--Transformation" (VHS), 1994 (Box 25)
      This film is about the transformation through the NCC to an ecumenical approach for addressing social justice issues. The film demonstrates how the ecumenism of the NCC works.
    - "Waiting Upon the Lord--Transformation" (U-matic: 3 copies; one a Master), 1994; 3 (Box 66, Item barcode 39002098995922)
    - "Waiting Upon the Lord--Transformation" (D-2) (Box 141)
  - Worship Services
    - "Billy Graham"; Raw footage from Billy Graham's worship service with the NCC - Part 1 (Beta), Sep. 27, 1991; 1 (Box 26, Item barcode 39002098994552)
    - "Billy Graham"; Raw footage from Billy Graham's worship service with the NCC - Part 2 (Beta), Sep. 27, 1991; 1 (Box 26, Item barcode 39002098994560)
    - "NCC Worship Service"; Raw footage from a small worship service, probably of NCC leaders. (Betacam SP: 1), Nov. 2, 1987; 1 (Box 67, Item barcode 39002098995955)
    - "Kisgkovsky Installation" (Metal Powder Tape: 2 volumes), May 15, 1990 (Box 27)
    - "Service of Installation (for Rev. Joan Campbell)"; Raw footage from Rev. Campbell's installation as NCC General Secretary. (VHS: 2 volumes), May 14, 1991 (Box 25)
    - "Service of Installation (for Rev. Joan Campbell)" (U-matic: 3 volumes) (Box 68)
    - "Service of Installation (for Rev. Joan Campbell)" (U-matic S: 8 volumes) (Box 91–92)
    - "Dr. Syngman Rhee--Installation Service"; Raw footage of the installation of Dr. Rhee as the President of the NCC. (VHS (VTC): 4 volumes), Nov. 14, 1991 (Box 28)
    - "Dr. Syngman Rhee--Installation Service" Part 1 (Beta), Nov. 14, 1991; 1 (Box 27, Item barcode 39002098994578)
    - "Dr. Syngman Rhee--Installation Service" Part 2 (Beta), Nov. 14, 1991; 1 (Box 27, Item barcode 39002098994586)
    - "Dr. Syngman Rhee--Installation Service" Part 3 (Beta), Nov. 14, 1991; 1 (Box 27, Item barcode 39002098994594)
    - "Dr. Syngman Rhee--Installation Service" Part 4 (Beta), Nov. 14, 1991; 1 (Box 27, Item barcode 39002098994602)
  - Presentations
    - "The Hope of Your Calling"; Report of the General Secretary to the NCC General Board. (VHS: 2 copies; one a VTC), Nov. 11, 1992 (Box 28)
    - "The Hope of Your Calling" Report of the General Secretary to the NCC General Board (U-matic Master), 1992; 1 (Box 67, Item barcode 39002098995948)
    - "The Hope of Your Calling" (D-2) (Box 141)
    - "Images of an Agenda (NCC Governing Board Presentation)"; Through short excerpts of films, this film presents different issues to consider as an agenda for the NCC. (VHS), May 15, 1985 (Box 28)
    - "Images of an Agenda (NCC Governing Board Presentation)" (U-matic: 3 copies), 1985; 3 (Box 69, Item barcode 39002098995963)
    - "NCC General Secretary's Report, Portland, OR: In the Meantime (Jim Hamilton Report)"; Some glimpses of NCC activities. (VHS: 4 copies), Nov. 1990; 4 (Box 29, Item barcode 39002098994644)
  - Conferences
    - "NCC ('Gathering of Christians')"; This is raw footage from "Gathering of Christians": an ecumenical convocation. (U-matic S: 27 volumes) (Box 92–96)
    - "National Council of Churches--Birmingham, AL" - conference dealing with burned churches of the 1990s and their reconstruction - Part 1 (Beta), Sep. 27, 1996; 1 (Box 29, Item barcode 39002098994610)
    - "National Council of Churches - Birmingham, AL" - conference dealing with burned churches of the 1990s and their reconstruction - Part 2 (Beta), 1996 (Box 29, Item barcode 39002098994628)
    - "National Council of Churches - Birmingham, AL" - conference dealing with burned churches of the 1990s and their reconstruction - Part 3 (Beta), 1996; 1 (Box 29, Item barcode 39002098994636)
    - "National Council of Churches - Birmingham, AL" - conference dealing with burned churches of the 1990s and their reconstruction - Part 4 (Beta), 1996; 1 (Box 30, Item barcode 39002098994669)
    - "National Council of Churches - Birmingham, AL" - conference dealing with burned churches of the 1990s and their reconstruction - Part 5 (Beta), 1996; 1 (Box 30, Item barcode 39002098994677)
    - "National Council of Churches - Birmingham, AL" - conference dealing with burned churches of the 1990s and their reconstruction - Part 6 (Beta), 1996; 1 (Box 30, Item barcode 39002098994685)
    - "National Council of Churches - Birmingham, AL" - conference dealing with burned churches of the 1990s and their reconstruction - Part 7 (Beta), 1996; 1 (Box 30, Item barcode 39002098994693)
    - "National Council of Churches - Birmingham, AL" - conference dealing with burned churches of the 1990s and their reconstruction - Part 8 (Beta), 1996; 1 (Box 30, Item barcode 39002098994701)
    - "National Council of Churches - Birmingham, AL" - conference dealing with burned churches of the 1990s and their reconstruction - Part 9 (Beta), 1996; 1 (Box 30, Item barcode 39002098994719)
    - "National Council of Churches - Birmingham, AL" - conference dealing with burned churches of the 1990s and their reconstruction - Part 10 (Beta), No date; 1 (Box 30, Item barcode 39002098994651)
    - "NCC--Clergy/Laity"; Raw footage of the arrival of the Archbishop of Constantinople (accompanied by Archbishop Iakavos) at the NCC and a worship service with his participation. (Beta: 2 volumes), Oct. 30, 1990 (Box 31)
    - "NCC Souls of White Folk"; Raw footage of Mab Segrest giving a speech about how white people have damaged themselves through their racism (Betacam SP), Nov. 1, 1987; 1 (Box 71, Item barcode 39002098995989)
    - "New World Order"; This is raw footage from the NCC New World Order Project (Yale Divinity School's Tom Ogletree is one of the speakers) (VHS: 4 volumes), Nov. 15, 1991 (Box 34)
    - "New World Order" Part 1: Dr. Adams (Beta), No date; 1 (Box 31, Item barcode 39002098994727)
    - "New World Order" Part 2: Dr. Adams, No date; 1 (Box 31, Item barcode 39002098994735)
    - "New World Order" Part 4, No date; 1 (Box 32, Item barcode 39002098994743)
    - "New World Order" Part 5: Ogletree, Bellah, No date; 1 (Box 32, Item barcode 39002098994750)
    - "New World Order" Part 6: Bellah, No date; 1 (Box 32, Item barcode 39002098994768)
    - "New World Order" Part 7, No date; 1 (Box 32, Item barcode 39002098994776)
    - "New World Order" Part 8, No date; 1 (Box 32, Item barcode 39002098994784)
    - "New World Order" Part 9, No date; 1 (Box 32, Item barcode 39002098994792)
    - "New World Order" Part 10, No date; 1 (Box 33, Item barcode 39002098994800)
    - "New World Order" Part 11, No date; 1 (Box 33, Item barcode 39002098994818)
    - "New World Order" Part 12, No date; 1 (Box 33, Item barcode 39002098994826)
    - "New World Order" Part 13, No date; 1 (Box 33, Item barcode 39002098994834)
    - "New World Order" Part 14, No date (Box 33, Item barcode 39002098994842)
    - "New World Order" Part 15, No date; 1 (Box 33, Item barcode 39002098994859)
    - "New World Order" Part 16, No date; 1 (Box 33, Item barcode 39002098994867)
    - "New World Order" Part 17, No date; 1 (Box 34, Item barcode 39002098994891)
  - Social Awareness / Social Justice Issues
    - "We Mean to Stay: the Delta Ministry in Mississippi" (VHS: 2 copies), No date; 2 (Box 144, Item barcode 39002098996342, Box 146)
      This film starts out by showing the poverty for African-Americans in Mississippi. Racism is a major barrier to changing this condition. However, local African-American churches invite the NCC to come in and help implement changes, such as providing transportation for African-Americans to register to vote.
    - "We Mean to Stay: the Delta Ministry in Mississippi" (16 mm) (Box OV4)